lifx.co 2019-12-18

# Privacy Policy – LIFX US

**LAST UPDATED: AUGUST 20, 2019**

Lifi Labs, Inc. dba LIFX, a Delaware corporation, and its affiliates and subsidiaries (“ **LIFX** ”, “ **we** ”, “ **us** ”, or “ **our** ”) are committed to protecting your privacy.  Please read this Privacy Policy (the “ **Privacy Policy** ”) carefully to understand our policies and practices regarding your information and how we will treat it. This Privacy Policy is intended to inform you about the kind of information, including personally identifiable information, that we may collect from you in connection with your use of the Services and how, and for what purpose, we use that information.

This Privacy Policy is a part of and incorporated into the [LIFX Terms of Service](https://www.lifx.com/pages/terms-of-service) (the “ **Terms** ”). If any provision of this Privacy Policy is inconsistent or conflicts with any provision in the Terms, this Privacy Policy will control with respect to the subject matter hereof.  Capitalized terms used in this Privacy Policy but not defined in this Privacy Policy have the meanings given to them in the Terms.

**WHO WE (LIFX) ARE**

When we refer to or use “ **LIFX** ”, “ **we** ”, “ **us** ”, or “ **our** ” throughout this Privacy Policy it means the LIFX entity who is the controller of your data under this Privacy Policy, namely the LIFX entity with which you had, have, or will have a business relationship or that otherwise decides what data of yours is collected and how it is used. You may obtain

Please note that the LIFX subsidiaries and affiliates include companies in which Lifi Labs, Inc. dba LIFX has control, either through direct or indirect ownership. You may obtain a list of the LIFX subsidiaries and affiliates by contacting [privacy@lifx.com](mailto:privacy@lifx.com).

**HOW TO CONTACT US**

Please feel free to contact us if you have any questions about this Privacy Policy or LIFX’s information collection and security practices or to exercise any of your rights set out in this Privacy Policy by email: at [privacy@lifx.com](mailto:privacy@lifx.com) or by mail at: LIFX,350 Townsend Street #830 San Francisco, 94107, attention: Privacy Team.

**WHEN THIS PRIVACY POLICY APPLIES (AND WHEN IT DOESN’T)**

**This Privacy Policy applies when you** :

  * Visit or use the LIFX Website, LIFX App or our social media channels;

  * Purchase and use the LIFX Products;

  * Subscribe to our newsletters, marketing campaigns or participate in our surveys or giveaways;

  * Contact our customer support

  * Collaborate with us in a paid or unpaid partnership; or

  * Otherwise interact with us in your capacity as a customer.

**Unless otherwise stated in this Privacy Policy, this Privacy Policy does   _not_  apply**:

  * When you visit or use third party links and websites.
  * To information you share when you connect, integrate or use the LIFX Products with third party applications, integrations, or services.

**YOU GIVE US CONSENT**

By accessing or using the Services, or submitting information through the Services, you acknowledge and agree that by providing us Personal Information you (1) understand that you allow us to identify you; and (2) have read, understand, and agree to the terms of this Privacy Policy and you expressly consent to the collection, use, and disclosure of your Personal Information and Anonymous Information (as each term is defined below) in accordance with this Privacy Policy.

Some of the services we provide may be obstructed if you do not provide us the necessary Personal Information.  **IF YOU DO NOT AGREE WITH OUR POLICIES AND PRACTICES, UNLESS OTHERWISE STATED, YOUR CHOICE IS NOT TO USE OR ACCESS THE SERVICES.**

**DEFINING “PERSONAL INFORMATION”**

We collect data and information from you in connection with your use of the Services, which includes both Personal Information and Anonymous Information.

“ **Personal Information** ” is information that allows someone to identify or contact you, as well as any other non-public information about you that is associated with or linked to any of the foregoing, and can include, for example, an individual's first and last name, address, phone number, e-mail address, IP address, location or other personally identifiable details. Personal Information does not include Anonymous Data.

“ **Anonymous Information** ” means aggregated and/or anonymized data that is not associated with or linked to your Personal Information.  Anonymous Information does not, by itself, permit the identification of individual persons.

**PROTECTING YOUR PRIVACY**

We do not share, rent or sell your account information to any third party, except as expressly set forth in this Privacy Policy. Please help us protect your privacy by keeping your account information safe. Do not disclose your account password or login information to anyone and keep changing it periodically.  

**INFORMATION WE COLLECT AND HOW WE USE IT**

Depending on your interactions with us (for example, online, offline, over the phone, etc.) we may process different data about you. We may collect your data, for example, when you visit or use the LIFX Website, LIFX App or our social media channels, purchase and use the LIFX Products, subscribe to our newsletters, download a software update to the LIFX App or LIFX Products, contact our customer support, participate to our giveaways, promotions, surveys, and marketing campaigns or otherwise interact with us.

**INFORMATION YOU PROVIDE US**

**_Account & Log in Information_**

When you register an account for the LIFX App you are required to provide us your email address. In addition, when you access your account you provide us your log in ID, password or other security codes.

We may use the Personal Information you submit during the registration process to send you services-related communications.  In addition, to the extent permitted by applicable law, we may also use such Personal Information to send you electronic newsletters or promotional e-mails, unless you have requested not to receive such promotional communications from us as described below.

**_Purchase, Payment and Billing Information_**

When you purchase LIFX Products through the LIFX Website, our third party store provider (Shopify) and payment processor (as determined by your selected method of payment) will collect, on our behalf, your first and last name, email address, shipping and billing address, and complete credit card information or bank account information, that enables us to receive your payment and provide you with the LIFX Products.

_Payment Methods Currently Offered_ :

  * Affirm Repayments
  * Amazon Payments
  * American Express
  * Apple Pay
  * Discover
  * Diners Club
  * Google Pay
  * Jcb
  * Mastercard
  * PayPal
  * Shopify Pay
  * VISA

Our store provider and payment processing provider will retain this information to process your payments and as necessary to complete your purchase of the LIFX Products.

We may use such Personal Information to provide in order to ship you the LIFX Products and fulfill your order. In addition, to the extent permitted by applicable law, we may also use the email address provided to send you electronic newsletters or promotional e-mails, unless you have requested not to receive such promotional communications from us as described below.

**_Direct Communications with us, Feedback and Support_**

If you provide us Feedback or contact us via e-mail or through our “contact-us” forms, or contact us for support related inquiries, we will collect your first and last name, e-mail address and any information requested in our “contact-us” forms or support forms, as well as any other content included in the Feedback or your e-mail or in the contact-us” support inquiries you send to us. 

We may use Personal Information submitted in these communications to contact and respond to you and send you related services communications. Any Feedback you provide will be governed by the Terms.

**_Surveys, Giveaways and Marketing Campaigns_**

If you participate in our surveys, giveaways, or marketing campaigns, we may collect your name, mailing address, email, images and/or videos from which you may be identified, pictures and any other information requested and/or required with respect to your participation in the surveys, giveaways, and marketing campaigns.

We may use Personal Information submitted in connection with our surveys, giveaways and marketing campaigns to carry out the surveys, giveaways, and marketing campaigns and provide related marketing communications that we may think are of interest to you.

**_Additional Services and Communications_**

We may provide certain additional services and/or communications if you select such additional services and/or communications by opting-in to such additional services and/or communications using certain buttons provided in the user interface of our services.  We will collect the information specified for such additional services and/or communications in the user interface of our services where you opt-in by clicking on such buttons. We may use such Personal Information to send you the corresponding additional services and/or communications.

**INFORMATION COLLECTED AUTOMATICALLY**

When you visit or use the LIFX Website, LIFX App or LIFX Products, or subscribe to our newsletters, participate in our surveys, giveaways or marketing campaigns, or otherwise interact with us through our social media channels, in addition to the information you provide to us directly, we may collect information sent to us by your computer, mobile phone or other access device.

This information is used to (i) provide you the LIFX Website, LIFX App and other services requested by you, (ii) improve the LIFX Website, LIFX App and other services provided to you by us, (iii) notify user about updates to the Services, and (iv) contact you for our own internal marketing purposes.

For example, we may collect:

**_Device Information_**

Hardware model, IMEI number and other unique device identifiers, MAC address, IP address, operating system version, and settings of the device you use to access the Services.

**_Location Information_**

Your actual location (derived from your IP address or other location-based technologies), that may be collected when you enable location-based products or features through the LIFX Website, LIFX Apps or LIFX Products.

**_Log File Information_**

Log file information, which may include your internet protocol (IP) address, URLs of referring/exit pages, information you search for, click stream data, which pages areas of the Services you visit or use, access times, time and duration of your use of the Services.

**_Cookies and Other Tracking Technologies_**

A cookie is a small piece of data (text file) that a website – when visited by a user – asks your browser to store on your computer or device in order to remember information about you, such as your language and/or currency preference or login information. LIFX may use similar techniques, such as pixels, web beacons etc., which we will refer to collectively as “cookies”. Where required by applicable law, we will obtain your consent prior to setting cookies (except for strictly necessary cookies).

Please refer to our [Cookie Policy](https://www.lifx.com/pages/cookie-policy) for more information about the types of cookies and tracking technologies that we use, and why, on and through the Services, and how to accept and reject them.

**_Google Analytics_**

We also utilize Google Analytics, a web analysis service provided by Google, to better understand your use of our Services. Google Analytics collects information such as how often users visit the LIFX Website, what pages they visit and what other sites they used prior to visiting. Google uses the data collected to track and examine the use of our Services, to prepare reports on its activities and share them with other Google services.

Google may use the data collected on or through the Services to contextualize and personalize the ads of its own advertising network. Google’s ability to use and share information collected by Google Analytics about your visits to the LIFX Website and use of the Services is restricted by the [Google Analytics Terms of Use](https://www.google.com/analytics/terms/us.html) and the [Google Privacy Policy](https://www.google.com/policies/privacy/).

Google offers an opt-out mechanism for the web available [here](https://tools.google.com/dlpage/gaoptout/).

Please refer to our [Cookie Policy](https://www.lifx.com/pages/cookie-policy) for more information about the types of cookies and tracking technologies that we use, and why, on and through the Services, and how to accept and reject them.

**_Web Beacons  _**

Pages within the LIFX Website, LIFX App, and our e-mails may contain small electronic files known as web beacons (also referred to as clear gifs. pixel tags and single-pixel gifs) that permit us, for example, to count users who have visited those pages or opened an e-mail and for other related website statistics (for example, recording the popularity of certain content and verifying system and server integrity). This information is used to enable more accurate reporting, improve the effectiveness of our marketing, and improve the Services. 

We do not use web beacons to store or link to Personal Information. For more information on LIFX’s use of web beacons please refer to our [Cookie Policy](https://www.lifx.com/pages/cookie-policy).

**_Services usage information_**

This is information about how you are accessing and using the Services, which may include administrative and support communications with us and information about the workspaces, channels, people, features, content, and links you interact with, and what third party integrations you use (if any).

**INFORMATION COLLECTED FROM OTHER SOURCES**

To the extent permitted by applicable law, in addition to the LIFX Website and LIFX App, we may also obtain information about you from other sources, such as joint marketing partners, social media platforms and other third parties. For example, depending on your social media settings, if you choose to connect your social media account to your LIFX App account, certain data from your social media account will be shared with us, which may include data that is part of your profile.

**Anonymous Information**

We may create Anonymous Information records from Personal Information by excluding information (such as your name) that would otherwise make such data personally identifiable to you. We may use Anonymous Information at our discretion and for any purpose.   When we provide or use this information, we employ procedures so that the data does not identify you and we contractually prohibit recipients of the data from manipulating the data in a way that would re-identify it back to you.

**HOW YOUR INFORMATION IS SHARED**

We will share your Personal Information with third parties only in the ways that are described in this Privacy Policy. We consider this information to be a vital part of our relationship with you. There are, however, certain circumstances in which we may share your Personal Information with certain third parties without further notice to you, as set forth below.

**_Service Providers_**

We may provide your information to third party service providers (such as, but not limited to, our cloud service, data storage, e-commerce, payment processors and shipping and distribution providers) who require the information to perform services for us in order to provide you the Services. These third party service providers are required not to use your Personal Information other than to provide the services requested by us.

**_Affiliates_**

To provide the Services and other various services to you, we may use the efforts of our parent company, and any subsidiaries, joint ventures, or other companies, existing or formed in the future, under a common control (collectively, “ **Affiliates** ”). We may share some or all of your Personal Information with our Affiliates in which case we will require our Affiliates to comply with this Privacy Policy.

**_Business Transfers_**

As we develop our business, we might sell or buy businesses or assets. In the event we are acquired by or merged with a third party, we reserve the right to transfer or assign the information we have collected from our users as a part of such merger, acquisition, sale, or other change of control.  In an event of our bankruptcy, insolvency, reorganization, receivership, or assignment for the benefit of creditors’ rights generally, your Personal Information may be transferred by the trustee.  If LIFX or any of its Affiliates is acquired by or merged with a third party, that third party will possess the Personal Information in LIFX’s or its Affiliate’s possession and will assume the rights and obligations regarding your Personal Information as described in this Privacy Policy.

**_Other Third Parties_**

We may share Personal Information with our headquarters and affiliates, business partners and professional advisors such as banks, insurance companies, auditors, lawyers, accountants, other professional advisors, to whom it is reasonably necessary or desirable for us to disclose your data for the purposes described in this Privacy Policy. We may also make certain Anonymous Data available to third parties for various purposes, including for business or marketing purposes or to assist third parties in understanding our users’ interest, habits, and usage patterns for certain programs, content, services, advertisements, promotions, and functionality available through the Services.

**_Other Disclosures_**

Regardless of any choices you make regarding your Personal Information (as set forth below), we may disclose your Personal Information (i) to respond to subpoenas, warrants, court orders, lawful requests or legal process, (ii) to establish or exercise our legal rights or defend against legal claims or protect other users, (iii) in order to investigate, prevent, or take action regarding illegal activities, suspected fraud, or as otherwise required by law, or (iv) to investigate, prevent, or take action regarding any violation of this Privacy Policy or the Terms.

**THIRD WEB BEACON, BUTTONS, LINKS & WEBSITES**

**_Third Party Web Beacons and Third Party Buttons_**

We may display third-party content on or through the Services, including third-party advertising. Third-party content may use cookies, web beacons, or other mechanisms for obtaining data in connection with your viewing of the third party content on the Service. Additionally, we may implement third party buttons, such as Facebook, Instagram, Twitter or other social media “share” buttons, that may function as web beacons even when you do not interact with the button. Information collected through third-party web beacons and buttons is collected directly by these third parties, not by LIFX. Please consult such third party’s data collection, use, and disclosure policies for more information.

**_Third Party Links to Websites_**

The LIFX Website contains links to other third party websites. The fact that we link to a website is not an endorsement, authorization or representation of our affiliation with that third party. We do not exercise control over third party websites. These other websites may place their own cookies or other files on your computer, collect data or solicit Personal Information from you. Other sites follow different rules regarding the use or disclosure of the Personal Information you submit to them. We are not responsible for the content, privacy and security practices, and policies of third-party sites or services to which links or access are provided through the Services. We encourage you to read the privacy policies or statements of the other websites you visit.

**YOUR RESPONSIBILITIES, PRIVACY RIGHTS AND CHOICES**

**_Your Responsibilities_**

While LIFX is committed to protecting your privacy, it is your responsibility to ensure that to the best of your knowledge the information and data you provide us is accurate, complete and up-to-date. It is also your responsibility that in the event you share Personal Information of other people with us, you collect such Personal Information in compliance with local legal requirements and that you have the appropriate consent to share such Personal Information. At a minimum, you should inform any such people about this Privacy Policy and obtain their consent prior to sharing their Personal Information with LIFX.

**_Changes and Deletion of your Data_**

To the extent we provide you with access to and control of your information (for example, to update modify or, to the extent legally permissible, delete it), we strongly encourage you to take control of your information. 

In certain jurisdictions you have the right to request access and receive information about the Personal Information we maintain about you, to update and correct inaccuracies in your Personal Information, to restrict or object to the processing of your Personal Information, to have the information blocked, anonymized or deleted, as appropriate, or to exercise your right to data portability to transfer your Personal Information to another company. Those rights may be limited in some circumstances by local law requirements. In addition to the above-mentioned rights, you also have the right to lodge a complaint with a competent supervisory authority subject to applicable law.

If you would like to access, review, update, rectify, and delete any Personal Information we hold about you, or exercise any other data subject right available to you under applicable data protection laws and regulation, you can do so by submitting your request in writing by email: at [privacy@lifx.com](mailto:privacy@lifx.com) or by mail at: LIFX, 585 Broadway, Redwood City, 94063, attention: Privacy Team.

We will do our best to address your request in time and free of charge, except where it would require a disproportionate effort. In certain cases, we may ask you to verify your identity before we can act on your request. If you are unsatisfied with the reply received, you may then refer your complaint to the relevant regulator in your jurisdiction.

Please note that we may still use Anonymous Information that does not identify any individual and that even if you have requested deletion of your information, we may retain such information to the extent permitted by applicable law as further described in the section title “ _Data Deletion and Retention_ ” below. 

**_Cookies_**

You can accept or reject cookies by adjusting your web browser controls. Please consult our [Cookie Policy](https://www.lifx.com/pages/cookie-policy) for more information about our use of cookies and how to accept and reject them.

**_Marketing Communications_**

If you decide at any time that you no longer wish to receive such marketing communications from us, please follow the unsubscribe instructions provided in any of the communications. You may also opt out from receiving commercial email from us by sending your request to us by email at [privacy@lifx.com](mailto:privacy@lifx.com). Please be aware that, even after you opt out from receiving commercial messages from us, you will continue to receive administrative messages from us regarding the Services.

Where required by law, we obtain your consent for the processing of certain Personal Information collected by cookies or similar technologies, or used to send you direct marketing communications, or when we carry out other processing activities for which consent may be required. If we rely on consent for the processing of your Personal Information, you have the right to withdraw it at any time and free of charge. When you do so, this will not affect the lawfulness of the processing before your consent withdrawal.

**_Services-Related Communications_**

If you have registered an account for the LIFX App or if you have contacted us for support or for other reasons, you may not, despite your indicated e-mail preferences, “opt-out” of other services-related communications regarding your account, support requests, or any payments made, or to be collected, by you, including receiving notices of any updates to our Terms or this Privacy Policy, except by terminating your account.

**_California Residents – Shine the Light Law_**

Residents of California are entitled to ask us for a notice identifying the categories of Personal Information which we share with our affiliates and/or third parties for marketing purposes, and providing contact information for such affiliates and/or third parties. If you are a California resident and would like a copy of this notice, please submit a written request to: [privacy@lifx.com](mailto:privacy@lifx.com).

**INTERNATIONAL TRANSFERS**

LIFX is based in the United States. Personal Information that we collect may be transferred to, and stored at, any of our affiliates, partners or service providers which may be inside or outside the European Economic Area (“ **EEA** ”) and Switzerland, including the United States and Australia. By submitting your information to us, you agree to such transfers. Your Personal Information may be transferred to countries that do not have the same data protection laws as the country in which you initially provided the information. When we transfer or disclose your Personal Information to other countries, we will protect that information as described in this Privacy Policy.

With regard to transfers from the EEA to other countries that are not are recognized by the European Commission as providing an adequate level of protection, we have put in place adequate measures to protect your data, such as organizational and legal measures (e.g. standard contractual clauses approved by the European Commission). You may obtain a copy of these measures by contacting us at [privacy@lifx.com](mailto:privacy@lifx.com).

**DATA DELETION AND RETENTION**

We keep your data for the period necessary to fulfill the purposes for which it has been collected (for details on these purposes, see section titled “ _Information We Collect and How We Use It_ ” above). We also take measures to delete your Personal Information or keep it in a form that does not permit identifying you when this information is no longer necessary for the purposes for which we process it, unless we are required by law to keep this information for a longer period.

When determining the retention period, we take into account various criteria, such as the type of products and services requested by or provided to you, the nature and length of our relationship with you, possible re-enrollment with our products or services, the impact on the services we provide to you if we delete some information from or about you, mandatory retention periods provided by law and the statute of limitations.  In any event, we will retain and use your information as necessary to comply with our legal obligations, resolve disputes, and enforce our agreements. 

If you wish to delete your cloud account data, and revoke access to LIFX applications and devices you can do so at  <https://cloud.lifx.com/> 

When you delete your Customer Data, LIFX will confirm the deletion request and will commence removing the data iteratively from application and cloud storage, from both active and backup storage systems.  Deletion from application and cloud storage may occur immediately depending on how storage of the data has been configured and the timing of ongoing deletion cycles in the relevant data centers.

**SECURITY**

LIFX takes appropriate measures that are consistent with applicable data protection and data security laws and regulations to protect your information, including requiring our service providers to use appropriate measures to protect the confidentiality and security of your information and data. Depending on the state of the art, the costs of the implementation and the nature of the data to be protected, we employ technical and organization measures designed to prevent against risks such as accidental or unlawful destruction, accidental loss, unauthorized alteration, unauthorized disclosure or access, misuse, and any other unlawful form of processing of the Personal Information in our possession.

Please be aware that no security measures are perfect or impenetrable. We cannot guarantee that information about you will not be accessed, viewed, disclosed, altered, or destroyed by breach of any of our administrative, physical, and electronic safeguards, subject to requirements under applicable law to ensure or warrant information security. You acknowledge and agree that you provide your Personal Information at your own risk.  

We will make any legally-required disclosures of any breach of the security, confidentiality, or integrity of your unencrypted electronically stored Personal Information to you via email or conspicuous posting on our Site in the most expedient time possible and without unreasonable delay, consistent with (i) the legitimate needs of law enforcement or (ii) any measures necessary to determine the scope of the breach and restore the reasonable integrity of the data system , and any other disclosures that may be required under applicable law.

If you have any questions regarding our security measures please contact [privacy@lifx.com](mailto:privacy@lifx.com).

**CALIFORNIA AND DELAWARE "DO NOT TRACK" DISCLOSURES**

California and Delaware law require LIFX to indicate whether it honors “Do Not Track” settings in your browser concerning targeted advertising. LIFX adheres to the standards set out in this Privacy Policy and does not monitor or respond to Do Not Track browser requests.

**CHILDREN**

LIFX does not knowingly collect or maintain Personal Information from or about children under the age of thirteen (13) and the Services are not intended to be used by persons under thirteen (13). If you are under the age of thirteen (13), please do not use any of our Services at any time nor in any manner   If we learn that Personal Information of persons under thirteen (13) years of age has been collected on or through the Services, then we may deactivate the account and/or make the user content inaccessible. If you find that we have Personal Information about anyone below thirteen (13) years of age, please inform us at [privacy@lifx.com](mailto:privacy@lifx.com).

**CHANGES TO THIS PRIVACY POLICY**

This Privacy Policy may be amended by us from time to time.  If we make material changes to this Privacy Policy, we will use all reasonable efforts to notify you of such changes by posting the revised Privacy Policy on the LIFX Website or through the user interface of the LIFX App or by notifying you by email if you have provided it to us.  Your continued use of the Services after such notification of changes as described above will constitute your agreement to such changes. If you object to any change, your sole recourse shall be to immediately terminate your account and/or cease all access and use of the Services.

**QUESTIONS AND ADDITIONAL INFORMATION**

Please feel free to contact us at [privacy@lifx.com](mailto:privacy@lifx.com) if you have any questions about this Privacy Policy or LIFX’s information collection and security practices.

**©  2018 Lifi Labs, Inc. All rights reserved.**
